Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today
we're going outside for our lesson.
That's right today we are gardening.
We are going to set up our own garden.
Okay that means growing plants and maybe
even food. So let's take a listen to this
dialogue and we'll be back in
a moment to talk more about it.
I've decided to grow
my own garden. What?
You don't know the first
thing about gardening.
On the contrary I've been reading
a lot of books about the subject.
Oh yeah tell me then smarty pants.
How do you do about setting up your garden?
Well first I need to buy some things
such as fertilizer, seeds and tools.
What type of tools? You know the basics.
A rake, shovel, spade and a hoe.
Right well it seems like you have
all your bases covered. What's next?
I'll till the soil and then sow the seeds.
I'll then add some fertilizer and voila.
Gardening all done. Well
good luck with your garden
especially considering
we're in the dry season
and it won't rain for
the next three months.
All right we're back
so a lot of vocab related
to gardening we
mentioned a lot of tools
and we're going to explain a lot of
those now on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay so gardening has
some very special tools
like you said Marco.
The first one is one
that I am not well it's
actually not a tool
it's a part of gardening.
Something that we use
to help the plants grow
and I really don't like
it because it smells bad.
Exactly it smells kind
of bad and it has a very
strong smell and
that is called fertilizer.
So basically fertilizer
is something that you
use in a garden to help
the plants grow better.
Right I think it has
a lot of vitamins and
minerals that that the
plant needs to grow better,
faster, stronger. Exactly fertilizer. Okay
good and well now we're going to mention
four tools that we use in gardening
basic tools. The first one being a rake.
A rake. Rake. So a rake
is actually something
that's very common in
most houses especially
houses with a yard or
a garden. It's not just
a gardening tool but it
is something that has a
long handle and we use
it to clear the ground of
rocks or leaves. Right so just imagine
it's kind of like a big brush or a garden.
It collects things right. Right
it's like a big brush that's
it's pulling things out
of the ground or away
from the ground
especially in the fall like
October or November
when all the leaves fall off
the trees and you have
to you have to take them
off the grass you use
a rake to pull them.
So you can you use a rake to pull them and
you also call the action of using a rake.
You say you rake the garden. To
rake. That's right so to rake the leaves.
I hate raking the leaves.
All right and now the other
tool that we have is very common
not only in gardening
but for construction work
for many things you
have a shovel. Shovel.
So a shovel is basically
a big metal spoon. Right.
And you use it to to
make a hole in the ground.
Exactly so as we say we use it a lot in
gardening to make holes for maybe the plants
but also in construction
if you want to make a hole
in the ground things
like this you use a shovel.
And now a smaller version
of the shovel that you
use only with your hand.
This is called a spade.
A spade. So this is
very small like you said
and it's actually special
because of its shape.
A spade has a point. A shovel is round and
a spade has a point and what's interesting
Marco is it's actually very
common somewhere else.
In cards. That's right in cards.
So cards to have different
shapes. One is a heart.
One is a diamond. One of them is a
spade. So the one that's that's pointy.
That's called a spade and it's used
for digging kind of precision holes.
Right exactly. So maybe
you don't want to use
a big shovel if you want
to make maybe a small
hole in the ground
you would use a spade.
And now our last tool
has kind of a funny spelling.
It's H.O.E. and it's
pronounced ho. Ho.
So again this is a tool with
a very long handle and you
use it to maybe make
the ground softer or to
turn up the ground. So
when you're first starting
to plant a garden the
ground is very hard.
Very tough. Right. And
this is a really important tool
for that period because you
can basically turn up the ground.
You're not digging anything
but you're mixing up the
dirt a little bit to make it softer.
Okay very good. So that's when
you use this tool. It's kind
of a dirt or a soil mixer.
You can also pull
out those nasty weeds
with a ho. Okay good.
So for key tools that we
have just taken a look at
now but now let's move on
to two verbs that are
basically very important
when you're talking
about gardening and all this
is as you mentioned you
talked about mixing the
soil and in the next
line we see that it says
out till the soil. To till. Okay so basically
this is a way of turning up that soil
but you're doing it
kind of in lines right.
So you're you're mixing up
the soil and making it soft.
You're preparing the
soil for planting and
so you till the soil. Soil
of course in this case
is that dirt it's
earth. Right it's earth.
So to till is to prepare it for
planting. Till the soil that's right.
Till the soil. Okay and what do we do after
the soil has been tilled? Well then we
sew the seeds. Okay
so seeds are baby plants
basically and we sew the
seeds when we sew the seeds
we're putting the
seeds into the ground.
So that's basically planting
the seeds you can say we plant
the seeds or we sew the seeds.
Okay and the opposite of sewing.
The opposite of
sewing is reaping
R E A P to reap. So we
actually have a phrase in English.
This is very very famous
very common. We say
you reap what you sew. You reap what you
sew that's right. So you basically collect
what you planted and that's
kind of what you do in life.
So we say if you
haven't planted anything
good you're not gonna
reap anything good. Exactly.
It's a very popular
phrase. All right so we've
covered a lot of vocab
here. Why don't we go back
listen to the dialogue
again and we'll be back with
fluency builder. I've decided
to grow my own garden.
What? You don't know the
first thing about gardening.
On the contrary I've been reading a lot of
books about the subject. Oh yeah tell me
then smarty pants. How do you
go about setting up your garden?
Well first I need to buy some things
such as fertilizer, seeds and tools.
What type of tools? You
know the basics. A rake, shovel,
spade and a hoe.
Right. Well it seems like
you have all your bases
covered. What's next?
I'll till the soil and then sew the seeds.
I'll then add some fertilizer and voila,
gardening all done. Well
good luck with your garden
especially considering
we're in the dry season
and it won't rain for
the next three months.
All right we're back and
we have four phrases for
you on fluency builder
and we're going to take a
look at those now. Fluency
builder. This first phrase
is useful in any
conversation I think especially
if you're trying to
compress somebody.
So basically one person in this
dialogue says you know what
you don't know the first
thing about gardening.
That means you don't know
anything about gardening
and what does he say in
response? On the contrary.
On the contrary. So the
contrary means the opposite.
So basically this means
the opposite is true.
Right. You're basically
saying I disagree what you
were saying is false.
It's actually the opposite.
So maybe I have a feeling
Marco that it's going
to rain tomorrow.
Actually on the contrary I
saw in the news that it's going
to be very sunny tomorrow.
Oh that's good news.
So that's a way of
maybe politely disagreeing
with someone or saying
to someone that well
you're wrong. It's actually
the opposite of what you're
saying. Okay moving on
to our second phrase.
It's actually a colloquial
way of kind of making
fun of someone and you say
all right then smarty
pants. Okay smarty pants.
Don't think about this
too much. We're not talking
about pants actually.
Right. This is a way of
saying okay if you're so
smart then tell me that
it's it's sarcasm.
It's sarcasm exactly.
So this person says oh actually
I know a lot about gardening
and other person says
oh really smarty pants.
So you can actually
describe a person in this way.
Maybe a person that
thinks they know a
lot or or sometimes what you say a Mr. Know
It All. You also say it's a smarty pants.
Right. So someone who thinks they
know a lot or everything even. Right.
Mr. Know It All or
a or a smarty pants.
All right and our third phrase
is interesting because we
have a set up here
when the person says how
will you go about setting
up your garden. Right.
Okay. So to go about
doing something there's two
important parts of this.
So Marco the first part
is how how you use you go
about. This means how you do.
Right. So you're basically
how will you do this?
What's your approach?
So how will you go about
plus and then the verb in ING?
setting up your garden?
How will you start or what is your approach
to creating your garden? So maybe Marco
you want to write a book
and I can ask you well how
will you go about
starting your book? Right.
Or if I'm writing a book
you can say how will you go
about investigating for
your book? So what is the
approach you're going
to take? How will you do
it? How do you plan on how
do you plan on doing something?
Exactly. And our
final phrase here is
very commonly used
for all sorts of situations.
Basically if a person is
prepared you say well you
have all your bases covered. Okay. This is
a great phrase. It comes right from sports,
the common in English
to have sports phrases.
This comes from the sport
baseball. Right. So in baseball
the field is a diamond.
There are four corners
or four bases and the
runners have to go from one
base to the other one,
two, three, four and then
they get a point. But in
this case we're saying the
other team they have
their bases covered.
That means they're protecting
their bases. And in speech
we say if you have your
bases covered like you
said Marco you're very
well prepared. Right.
So you're ready, you're
prepared. You have really
planned out and thought
of what you're going to do.
So you have all
your bases covered.
So Marco for example you
just told me that it's going to
be sunny tomorrow. But
I think it still might rain.
So to have all my bases covered I want
to bring it umbrella anyway. Just in case.
Just in case. Or maybe you
have a presentation at work
and you've prepared your
power broom presentation.
You have your
drawings, your copies.
You have everything ready.
You have all your bases covered
for that meeting.
That's right. Okay.
So why don't we go back and
listen to our dialogue for the last
time and we'll be back
to talk a little bit more.
I've decided to grow
my own garden. What?
You don't know the first
thing about gardening.
On the contrary I've been reading a
lot of books about the subject. Oh yeah.
Tell me then smarty pants. How do
you go about setting up your garden?
Well first I need to buy some things
such as fertilizer, seeds and tools.
What type of tools? You
know the basics. A rake, shovel,
spade and a hoe.
Right. Well it seems like
you have all your bases
covered. What's next?
I'll till the soil and then sew the seeds.
I'll then add some fertilizer and voila,
gardening all done. Well
good luck with your garden
especially considering
we're in the dry season
and it won't rain for
the next three months.
Alright we're back. So
gardening is actually a very
popular thing in many
countries. I know many people
as well who prefer to
have their own personal
garden to grow their
own vegetables which they
say tastes a lot different
from the ones you buy
at the supermarket. They
do I think personally that
homegrown vegetables,
so vegetables that you grow
yourself tend to taste
a lot better than the
ones you get in the grocery
store. They also look different.
They're not as pretty. Right.
But that's because
they have less chemicals.
Yeah I think it's a very
popular thing and well not only
gardening your own
vegetables but some people just
enjoy it as a hobby too
to have some plants and
different types of
things in their backyard.
Yeah many people
say it's very relaxing.
You get to go outside.
You're in the sunshine.
It's very calming activity. Yeah
it seems like it's very relaxing.
A little bit boring
at times it is basically
you're waiting for your
plants to grow but I
imagine that once they
do you've accomplished it,
it must be great to see that
you've actually brought life.
I'm sure like 20 minutes every day
it's not so bad. Yeah yeah it's actually a
very interesting hobby
and we want to know if
well if in your country or
in your town do you have
enough space for a garden?
Do you like gardening
or maybe growing your
own food? I think that's a
very interesting topic. Yeah
let us know what you think.
Do you do this? Do you
have friends who garden?
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you
there. All right bye. Bye.